Wade Gooch

Phone: (614) 769-3388

E-mail: gooch.wade@gmail.com

Summary

I had the opportunity of beginning my IT career as an intern on a flagship Agile team, developing a brand new web application. I then began working as an automation developer, writing Cucumber scripts and object oriented Ruby code to perform testing against a Java Swing application. Now I am a front end developer using Angular JS.

Technologies

Experience with the following technologies:

- Object oriented programming | C# .NET | Visual Basic .NET | JavaScript
- JQuery | CSS | Twitter Bootstrap | ASP.NET MVC | WCF Services
- \bullet SQL/SQL Server Management Studio | \bullet HTML | \bullet Visual Studio | \bullet Microsoft Office
- Angular JS

Using these technologies, I have developed, modified, and debugged/analyzed object oriented applications and I have designed web pages using HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, and CSS. I have also written Ruby/Cucumber automation to test files and web services.

Education

Mount Vernon Nazarene University (Autumn 2015 to Present)

Major: Computer Science B.S. Graduation: Summer 2017

- I am continuing my studies in Computer Science, focusing on new languages/skills while also building on existing knowledge of Object Oriented programming and software development and Computer Science.

Columbus State Community College (Autumn 2012 to Autumn 2014)

Major: Computer Science A.A.S (Software Development specialization)

Graduated: December 12, 2014

- I have complete studies in Computer Science, focusing on Object Oriented programming, database programming, and application/software development. I consistently made the Dean's List and I am a member of the Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society.

The Ohio State University (Autumn 2011 to Spring 2012)

Major: Chemical Engineering, Electrical Engineering

I first began in the Chemical Engineering program, then switched to Electrical Engineering. After taking a programming class for Electrical Engineering, I decided to make the switch to Columbus State to pursue Computer Science.

Work History

Developer, IT Applications (12/8/2014 - Present)

Nationwide Application Development Center (3 Nationwide Plaza, Columbus OH)

- Currently a front end developer using Angular JS to build a new front-end for Retirement Plans application utilizing RESTful services.
- Formerly an Automation Developer writing object oriented Ruby/Cucumber tests against files and RESTful web services for rewrite of DC Direct (Public Retirement plans) Java Swing application
- Participate in cadence meetings for estimation and 3 Amigos, as well as Show & Tell presentations to business unit
- Develop business expertise in the financial sector as it pertains to Retirement Plans

Application Development Intern/Specialist (2/24/2014 -12/5/2014)

Department of Public Safety (1970 West Broad St., Columbus OH)

- Contributed to Hours Management System (HMS) application rewrite for Human Resources using ASP.NET MVC framework (C#) and Twitter Bootstrap
- Worked on a team using Agile methodologies
- Performed Test Driven Development (TDD) using Moq framework
- Participated in all cadence meetings for software analysis and solutions
- Utilized Team Foundation Server for repository and tracking purposes
- Contributed to and attended ODPS Agile University
- Was hired on briefly before accepting a position with Nationwide